AKINDEMOWO AYORINDE OLAYIWOLA (Mr.)

Address: 21, Daniel Makinde street Ketu Lagos, Nigeria

Email: Contact No: 07061943535

ayorinde223@gmail.com

A versatile, resourceful, result-oriented software enthusiast with 5+ years of work experience participating in the complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications and contributing constructively to the status quo of the industry by way of research and development.

SKILLS

Object Oriented Programming, Web Development, Building RESTFUL

Services, Unit Testing and Debugging, Microservices development, Building

Area(s) of Interest reusable packages (npm, laravel) to help others ease development

Programming Language(s)

Php(Laravel), C#(asp.net core), JavaScript, nodejs, Typescript, TypeORM, AdonisJS, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, mySQL,

PostgreSQL

Tools and

IDE: Visual studio, VS Code, PhpStorm

Technologies UsedOthers: Git, Google DevTools, CircleCl, Firebase, Visual Studio, Team

Foundation Server(TFS), Docker.

Technical Electives Web Data Management, Database Management, Blockchain, and

Cryptocurrency.

EDUCATION

Degree	University/Institute	Year
B. sc. (Computer science)	Federal University of Agriculture Abeokuta (FUNAAB)	2011 – 2015
High School	Proper Arsenal high school, Lagos Nigeria	2003 – 2009

Experience

PATRICIA TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED

(July 2019 - Present)

Senior Software Engineer

Building scalable systems to help facilitate wallet system, payment system, and cryptosystem with the aim to improve the business effectively using technologies like PHP laravel, nodejs

Duties:

- Working with Laravel framework PHP, Nodejs, Typescript
- Built Rate system that is used for several crypto rates Typescript
- Worked with Patricia Pay (Patricia Payment switch application)
- Wallet system (Naira wallet, Crypto Wallet)
- Build Patricia International (Ecommerce Web App)
- Integrating payment gateway to Patricia pay

(MAY 2018 - JUNE 2019)

NETPLUSDOTCOM

Mid Software Engineer

Managing and building payment solution Netpluspay

Duties:

- Building consumable web service to facilitate payment.
- Worked with Laravel framework PHP
- Worked with CodeIgniter framework PHP
- Worked with building scalable services with nodejs
- Building And Consuming Web services
- Designed and implemented using tools like PHP, MySQL, CSS, JavaScript, HTML, Ajax depending on project specifications
- Developed Front End Development (NetPlusPay.com)
- Integrating Nibbs payment API (Paylink.com)
- Integrating Payment solutions like (Interswitch, Visa, GtBank(Gtpay))

•

MUTUAL BENEFITS MICROFINANCE BANK

SEPTEMBER 2017 – MAY 2018

Junior Software Engineer

DUTIES:

- Database Administrator (Microsoft SQL) Addressing Script issues
- Asp.net building Banks website
- Unit Testing and Debugging banks Application
- Ensure data is secured and organized so analysts can easily locate information
- Create and administer databases
- Ensure databases operate smoothly and efficiently and fix errors or problems that may occur.
- Configuring and managing a Windows 2012 server in a domain environment
- Joining a Windows workstation to a Windows Domain
- Setting up basic services like Active Directory, DNS, and DHCP

INTERNSHIPS

SYSTEMSPECS NIGERIA LTD. 4th-8th Floor, 136 Lewis Street, Lagos, Nigeria.

(JULY 2014 - DECEMBER 2014)

- Worked with my team to design websites and web applications using (PHP, WordPress)
- Worked with the Document management system
- Redesign the companies website
- Computer-Based Testing/Exam System (PHP)

RECENT PROJECTS

A Microservice For Smart City EKO Open Source projects

(Nov 2020 - Present)

Building and managing 4 microservices (Authentication, Profile, Domain, Access service), using languages like Lumen PHP, Asp.net core, Nodejs and using Docker for each services.

An Artisan Web App

(completed)

https://handiwork.com.ng/

An App to request for an artisan built in Laravel (Backend), and ReactJs (FrontEnd)

A Social Club Web App

(completed)

https://metclub.netlify.app

A social club app built with laravel(backend) and React js(front end), the app also has Integration with SAGE Accounting. With the aim of creating customers (AR), generating invoice and statement account, getting each customers yearly spendings (GL), to name the few.

NPM Package (Patricia Auth Client)

https://www.npmis.com/package/patricia-auth-client

An Npm Package to manage Authentication setup for the company across node applications.

Laravel Package (Request Logger)

(Mar 2020)

Guide: self

RequestLogger is a Laravel Package for logging errors and monitoring every activity on the app And also makes it easy to log requests IP, agent(could be browser or postman), payload request, payload response, Time of execution, and URL in the database within any request call.

Wallet App (Sep 2019)

Guide: self

Built wallet app (nodejs sequelize & asp.net core) for managing electronic funds.

Payment web service (March 2018)

Building web service for payment (wakanow & netplus handshake)

E-bills Notification service

(Feb 2019)

Built A Dotnet core Ebills Notification web service(Rest) using Asp.net core (Netpluspay & Seven-Up Handshake)

An Ecommerce web App from scratch

(June 2019)

https://patriciauniverse.com/

Patricia international e-commerce web app (Laravel). An app to trade Giftcards.

Social App (March 2018)

Guide: self

A Social App (NODEJS, REACT, EXPRESS, MONGO)

PROJECT AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

DESIGN AND IMPLEMENTATION OF VOICE OVER WIRELESS LOCAL AREA NETWORK (VoWLAN)

(July 2018 - Present)

The specific objectives were:

- Study and examine the communication system used in COLPHYS (FUNAAB college)
- Design and implement standard network protocols and application logic that we will use to implement VoIP.
- Installation of asterisks as the Operating System
- Design and implement voice over internet protocol for varieties of soft phones and hard phones (assigning IP addresses)
- Test voice over wireless local area network (VoWLAN) communication between end devices.

Interests and Hobbies:

Soccer, Music, Surfing the internet, Software Development.